»ç¶û LOVE
If you want to suggest on subtitles, please contact me at dskim0727@gmail.com.
Year 2005. National Cancer Center
My name is Seo Young-Ran. I have been struggling with terminal cancer for 2 years.
I have a good reason to wash in my bed.
Feel good. / feel good?
I'm a good cleaner.
We will be married.
You are the most beautiful. I'm lucky. Wonderful!
Just after we decided to marry, we found out that I had a terminal cancer.
But he registered our marriage.
Now we are having a wedding ceremony.
While I am not so ugly, we will be married.
It was small but so much bigger than beginning.
It grows quickly.
uterus, arteries, lung, ovary, suprarenal, brain...
teeth, nose. everywhere...
so I will take a portrait photo before taking wedding photo.
Why have you put on?
Well... Just
We have decided to go out to prepare our wedding ceremony.
I'm so excited but he's not sure if it is good or not.
Are you a hunter?
I haven't been outside of the hospital for 1 month.
cold?
It's not cold at all.
It was beautiful afternoon. I forgot the pain because I was so excited.
I'm so pretty!
I am marrying a good girl but I'm not sure.
but it was my last outing.
YOU ARE MY DESTINY
Year 2006. Jiri Mountain
January 2006, We have new year at mountain Jiri.
We bought this house to have medical treatment.
We had newly-married life in this house.
I bring her Jiri mountain as I promised.
But her body is not here.
She just left some letters written in hospital.
She is not anywhere.
My watch stopped when she died.
She aske me to play this song just after she died.
.
when shed died, I went to a market to buy batteries.
I played the song and I was thinking something to do.
.
I wondered if I did everything she asked.
She was 28 years old.
She is such a precious girl as my life.
Year 2005. National Cancer Center
Last October, in the middle of automn.
I can remember her clearly.
She was university student when we found out the cancer.
Her dream was being a teacher.
Last autumn, she was still keeping the dream.
National Cancer Center
We got along together in the hospital.
She has pain on her ass because she is always lying.
It hurts. / trying to release pain.
Somebody might see. They might misunderstand. / Don't care.
It's better put a note on my ass saying that it hurts.
Actually, in this hospital, they always talking about me.
Because there are a few husband who stays beside his sick wife.
She was always laughing. She always made good mood.
but shed was very sick.
Radiotherapy equipment is put on her head.
The cancer is destroying her neuron.
What time is it now? Hasn't it finished?
Since we found the cancer, I've been taking care of her doing nothing.
Please buy me a ice cream after this treatment.
Ice cream again?
Need anything else?
Take care.
More operation is useless.
The only solution is Radiotherapy.
Doctor said that she would die within 3 month.
But she's been fighting for 2 years.
with pain of cancer and tough treatment.
This is the second radiotherapy.
How long should she take this pain?
Just after treatment we went to buy an ice cream.
she loves ice cream.
Doctor says don't take cold food because she has cancer in her lung.
but nothing else can soothe her now.
[Sometimes, I just want to die]
I can't see the end.
Yesterday, I just wanted to die.
My will is getting weaker.
Just want to quit but I must not.
Scary. It's 4th spitting out blood.
I might lose consciousness because of difficulty in breathing.
OK?
.
Can't breathe. blooding again...
It has passed just one month after last spitting out blood.
It's unpredicted.
One hour later, spitting out blood has finished.
I am terminal cancer patient even if I am pretending not.
Don't die now. wont you?
.
Cheer up!
feeling relieved and tired.
Sometimes, I just want to sleep forever.
but I must survive for him at any cost.
They removed 60 percent of my liver.
After 6 months, the cancer infected my lung.
Which part of my body is infected as well?
My lung bleeded
.
The cancer is getting stronger.
[I belive]
I don't accept any bad diagnosis.
They say she is dying but I don't belive them.
I want to go Sumjin river to eat shell.
.
I used to say that put my body Sumjin river.
I have changed my mind. / where?
.
I prefer Jiri mountain to Sumjin river.
Her finger has infected by cancer.
She is constantly talking about death.
Is there any good place? / don't know.
.
Anywhere in Jiri mountain?
Let's go out picnic. / sounds good.
.
I don't let her go now.
She is 9 years younger than me.
I met her 4 years ago. She was 24 years old. She joined staff of the market I worked for.
She was the last daughter, friendly and easy going.
I always asked him go out for dinner.
I temptated him. I'm shy
He always says that I was hooked because I was so innocent.
He was 34 years old. He lost his parents when he was a small boy, so he didn't afford to study.
He was fish sales person at a market.
Her parents hated me. Furthermore, I didn't deserve such a nice girl.
I was hopeless before I met her.
I didn't have any goal of life.
I was in my hard times before I met her.
I recognized that he hadn't been happy before. I felt his pain.
I promised him that 'I will make you happy.'
He will get to knnow what the happiness is.
After two years, the cancer troubled us.
She started losing hair. I decided cut my hair in advance.
I did everything that encourage her.
[A word that I can't say]
Without him, I can't live on.
I think I'm a bad girl. I haven't said that leave me and forget me.
scared. I shall die without him. I'm sure.
I'm very bad girl.
Her mother visits her every twice week.
.
They don't want her to stay in the hospital.
He has been taking care of her for 2 years.
Her mother cares him instead of her.
He is really pathetic. Her father agrees.
.
I and her father wanted him to leave her.
But he wanted to stay with her. and she liked that.
She really wants him. For my daughter, he should stay. It's a dilema.
It has passed two years.
Everytime she comes, he goes out.
It's hard to let him go out.
He is healty. He needs to refresh himself.
Death and living, nobody beats terrible illness.
Even the stongest love disapears somtimes.
People say that it is saying good-bye.
but I know where he is.
He left me last year.
I thought he had gone forever, but he came back next day.
I tried to stay close to her. It's natural.
.
He expected that it would be comfortable withou her, but it was not true.
He hardly goes out of the hospital.
The next day
Why are you waiting for him here
I just wanted.
.
Do you always wait for him outside?
Yes, everytime.
.
Do you want see him early?
Yes, When he sees me waiting, he is happy.
.
Honey!
You smell alcohol.
.
I can't live without him.
Did she eat much?
.
Something wrong.
Be patient.
.
Thanks god. It has stopped.
Good job!
One ice cream? half?
.
It's hard to digest.
Cold wind or cold food is a kind of poison to me.
.
I want to do many things.
You are telling me off because of one ice cream.
.
She is in her twenties.
I have many dreams. I have a man to love much.
But how long can I live?
How long have you not been out?
A month?
.
He hesitated because cold weather might be a poison to her.
If she gets a cold, it will be serious.
These days, she pushed him strongly to have a wedding ceremony.
Two years ago, when we decided to get married, her parents didn't accepted him.
but we decided to live together.
I reget I should have done this early. She's so happy.
.
Even if her life is timed, our love will last.
While we are alive, we have a right to love each other.
5 days before the wedding
They say when a lady is married, she will get healtier.
Don't cry.
.
She wants to leave a pretty image of her to the world.
We wanted to take a nice picture of her.
She's so beautiful. It's impossible to forget her.
Don't cry, stupid.
so beautiful.
.
impressed?
sure.
.
I've just realized that you are so beautiful.
After that she washs everday.
He washed you yesterday already. Why do you wash again?
.
He didn't wash at all.
I will wash just this part.
.
It looks clean, but she never stops without any reason.
but that was the last bath preparing death.
3 Dec 2005
One day to wedding.
Spitting blood is nothing.
Her mother wants to say something about her father.
He said that he would not go to the wedding.
.
saying that the wedding would make people cry twice.
He is wrong.
.
I expected he would come.
Am I happy to get married in the hospital?
.
He would not understand me.
They couldn't get married because of her father.
He thinks that it's not fair to get married before death.
He might be right, but the wedding is my last wish.
.
Is he worring as I?
Is he scared as me? All he has to do is just coming.
.
I quit. He is right. I might die tomorrow.
pain in my head.
.
Stop crying!
Can't open mouth. It's paralyzed.
4th Dec 2005
3pm 4th Dec 2005, The wedding was canceled.
They visit the hostpital.
The wedding was canceled, but they wanted to see her.
She is concious but can't raise hand.
.
Her father
sorry. love you.
5 Dec 2005
.
pain on my leg
drink
.
banana and drink
drink, banana, ice cream
.
but most her organ has stopped working. She's dying.
Pain... Water... Help me...
Help me...
Nothing I can do.
Please hug me.
The next day. 6th Dec 2005
I have a wish...
.
Saying good bye with smiling face just before I die.
and he said that "you can do it".
.
I want to die in happiness.
They say that a person who can smile when she die is a happy person.
.
I was comfortable
When I saw her resting in peace
.
throwing all sadness.
But she is in a small and dark space.
.
I'm really sorry for everything.
To live is nothing but a sin.
.
8 Dec 2005 Jiri Mountain
He came back to Jiri mountain with her.
At this mountain, we lived together.
While they lived here, They hoped to overcome.
He buries her in their memory.
Are you following me, my wife Seo Young-Ran? I say good bye now.
Bye
My love.
You've had hard times.
I hope, in the next life, you get a heathy body.
.
You are always in my mind.
1 May 2006 Jiri Mountain
It has passed 5 months since she has gone. I've met many of her in this place.
This round pebble reminds me of her.
This pebble is me.
I live just same as she was alive.
To remember is much easier than to forget.
Sometimes I find unexpected gift.
Without date.
Do you want me to wash your face?
This house cherishs her as well.
.
Nothing is fresh as her in my heart.
It's the last letter written in 1 month before wedding.
My heart is still beatting as if our love has just begun.
Even if myI life is short, but I'm sure I love you more than anyone else.
And Thanks to you, my life was beautiful.
I always thank you from the begining.
I love you from the bottom of my heart.
Once she said "I wish there are many flowers".
.
Now I know she is my destiny. I believe.
These flowers are sign of our love.
when these flowers bloom,
I wish she could smell the scent in the heaven.
»ç¶û LOVE
Where there is love,
there is life.
(Mohandas K. Gandhi)